Andrew A Hamlin

aahamlin@gmail.com (860) 810 - 6538 https://aahamlin.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewahamlin

SUMMARY

With a background in full stack application and distributed system development from tech startups to a Fortune 100 company, I am a champion for software craftsmanship and servant leadership. I strive to build team cultures of humility, respect, integrity and accountability.

As an engineer and manager, I have worked on greenfield, legacy and sustained engineering projects using Waterfall, XP, Agile, & Lean methodologies; supported many partner relationships and launched many teams onto paths of continuous improvement.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr Software Development Manager Gerber Technology, LLC 2018 - present

Coach individuals and teams in Agile-Lean improvements. Decreased lead time (-77%), cycle time (-81.5%) and rejection rate (-5.3%) over last 3 product releases. Collaborate with Product, QA and Dev teams on planning and delivery of 2D/3D CAD roadmap and tp strategically address technical debt. Champion adoption of a CI/CD workflow using Git, AWS CodeCommit, Jenkins including unit and integration test automation. Leading technical integration of a digital avatar platform. Manage 7 developers and 10 offshore.

Software Development Manager Sailpoint Technologies 2016 - 2018

Worked with senior leadership to improve all design, build and test procedures; increasing predictability and code quality. Scrum master of 2 teams; totaling 16 dev & test engineers. Established business process and added 4 languages from a new vendor. Led teams developing Java, SQL, Angular.js, REST API, SCIM API, OAuth 2.0, Multi-Factor Authentication with Duo and RSA, credential cycling with CyberArk and BeyondTrust, and Accessibility compliance with Section 508 and WCAG 2.

Software Development Manager/Team Lead Caradigm USA, LLC 2013 - 2016

Delivered 2 products to market. Led 6-person team developing an SDK for RFID Reader integration with Linux VDIs from Dell Wyse, HP SmartZero and Teradici using Java, C, and Python and extended build system support for ARM & Intel processors.

Andrew A Hamlin

Led 10-person team developing an Identity Governance solution including Microsoft SQL w/ SSIS, MVC5, HTML/CSS, REST API and Knockout.js. Reached 70% coverage w/ unit and integration tests and a fully automated build-deploy-test workflow using Team Foundation Server, Microsoft Test Manager and Hyper-V systems.

Sustaining Engineering Manager

Caradigm USA, LLC

2012 - 2013

Drove 6 month turn-around of Sustaining Engineering operations with team of 2 senior engineers and 6 offshore, to consistently meet all Service Level Agreements; received *Employee Recognition Award*. Facilitated cross-functional meetings to manage escalations from Professional Services and Customer Support organizations to engineering team.

Software Development Engineer II

Microsoft Corporation

2010 - 2012

Spear-headed initial learning, adoption and training during transition of technology stacks from Linux, Java, Perl to Windows, C#/.NET, WCF, WPF, PowerShell.

Senior Software Engineer

Sentillion, Inc

1999 - 2010

Developed and Architected (portions of) Enterprise IAM solution with 99.999% uptime; a *KLAS Top 20* product. Direct customer support in startup environment.

VOLUNTEER

Software Development Elective, Instructor

The Master's School	The Master's School	West Simsbury, CT	2014 - 2015
---------------------	---------------------	-------------------	-------------

YMCA Swim Official

YMCA of Greater Hartford Granby, CT 2008 - 2014

EDUCATION

B.S. Management and Information Technology

Daniel Webster College Nashua, NH